Just for the record, do you have any
more snaps at quarterback left in you?
>> If they need me, I got you. I tell you,
>> hey, I got an arm, so armor ain't going
to leave.
>> All right, friends. Here we go. It is
the new league year. Happy New Year to
you and yours edition. What are you
doing? Of the best podcast.
>> Merry New Year
>> available. Jason Gibbs presented by
Bullseye Event Group. For award-winning
game day experiences, visit
bullseyeventgroup.com.
Hi there, friends. Happy New Year. My
name is Andrew Siciliano. We did not get
the tuxedos and the party hats and the
streamers and the confettes. There will
be no making out in Times Square. It is
just me, your humble host, Jason Gibbs,
also a host, sometimes humble, uh, with
the best podcast available. Gibbe, happy
new year, buddy.
>> Merry new year, Mr. New. Away we go with
and away we go season.
>> And away we go. Coming up, the pride of
Monroeville,
Alabama.
>> Titus Howard, the Browns new offensive
lineman. But where is going to join BPA?
Where will Titus Howard play on the
line? Or where would he like to play on
the line? Let's phrase it. Let's phrase
it that way. coming up shortly right
around the corner on BPA as we open up
the new league year and a friendly
reminder because maybe we have to remind
other teams like the Ravens and the
Raiders the new league year did not
become official until 400 p.m. Eastern
time. So, Gibbez, you have been uh
putting together CBD Cleveland Browns
Daily these last couple of days and
right here, longtime listener. Um it is
it is a challenge because as all this
news kind of sort of comes across the
high-speed newswire,
not all of it is actually locked in
until 400 p.m. Eastern time. We could
say confidently, however, that the
Browns have added Titus Howard. That's a
trade with the Texans, a fifth round
draft pick going back to Houston. The
Browns had three. And they have added
former Chargers first round pick.
Offensive uh guard Zion Johnson and
former Packers
O lineman played all over the place.
Guard and center, most notably center
last year, Elton Jenkins. Your thoughts,
sir?
>> And we'd be we can't short change our
guy. We brought back Kevin Jenkins as
well, bolstering that Browns offensive
line here in 2026. A complete makeover
on the Browns offensive line. Now, where
all these pieces fit, I think it's to be
determined. I mean, who's playing guard,
who's playing tackle, who's playing
center? We have a lot of guys that can
play a lot of different positions, but
the Browns uh clearly had a focus going
into free agency, and it was to revamp
and improve that Browns offensive line
from a year ago.
>> Yeah. So, let let's give it the headline
like this. The Browns offensive line
right now is is better and hopefully
healthier than it was uh a year ago. We
came into the season a year ago with a
new offensive line coach in Mike
Bloomgrren and this idea that hey you're
getting back to the ground and pound
Joel Batonio's words the 2020 20221
install that kind of offense Brown's
obviously a playoff team in 2020 that we
had seen five to six years ago it for a
litany of reasons didn't necessarily get
off the ground. Joel Batonia was a rock
at left guard. Uh Ethan Posig battled
and battled until he tore Achilles late
in the season. Right guard was somewhat
of a revolving door between Wyatt Teller
and obviously Tevin Jenkins there as
well for a litany of reasons. Dwan Jones
started at the left side, ended up on
the right side, then he was the victim
of a low blow that was not flagged. It
should have been flagged and then he
hurt his knee and he was done for the
year. The offensive line never came into
place like we thought it would come into
place. these additions and I think it's
key given for the most part in the
middle of the line. Titus Howard played
a lot of guard last year although he has
been predominantly a right tackle. You
build a line from the inside out.
They're not all young pieces. Although
Zion is only four now soon to be five
years removed from being taken number 17
overall. The other two pieces, Jenkins
and Howard, are 30year-old pieces, but
you shell out the cash and you hope that
you are reliable and big in the middle
of your offensive line.
>> Yeah. And they I go back to Emory Hunt
on Cleveland Browns daily at the NFL
combine a few weeks ago. He said a lot
of a lot of talk about tackle, tackle,
tackle. You got to have tackles. You got
to have really good tackles.
>> And he's right. But he also said
everything starts inside like you just
said, guard center. You got to have a
good middle of that offensive line and
the Browns have clearly made that a
priority. Now, as of this point, we
don't know what Joel Batonio is going to
do.
>> Knock out wood. Maybe hopefully he comes
back, but if not, um, you know, you've
put yourself in a position where you've
got a lot of stability inside and you've
got some depth and you have guys that
could play multiple positions. And you
know, they I they clearly were focused
on what they needed to do here in free
agency to kick things off and that was
the priority needs to be getting that
offensive line back to the high level
that it's been over the last few years
and unfortunately was not last year for
a number of different reasons.
>> Yeah. and and this if you look at pick
six or you look at pick pick 24
regardless and we we discussed this at
the combine this is a right tackle draft
not a left tackle draft now doesn't mean
there aren't left tackles there
certainly are but even look at CC Minoa
Francis Minoa the right tackle there uh
for the University of Miami you saw him
play deep into the playoffs obviously
playing in the national championship
game the the guy is a mer there are a
lot of people that think he might be
better served kicked inside playing
right guard. Look at um Spencer Fano at
uh at Utah. He was taking snaps at
center at the end of the combine. He's a
right tackle. Some people think he's a
right guard. He could end up playing
center. Flexibility here. Position flex,
I think, is the key. Is there a world in
which Joel Batonio comes back? Yeah.
Well, how how does that fit with the
moves the Browns have made? It would
likely, and this is just my estimation,
fit like this. So it would go Batonio
obviously back into his comfortable
position into his comfortable recliner
at left guard. Then Elton Jenkins at
center then Zion Johnson at right guard
and then Titus Howard at right tackle.
This is just me spitballing here. Zion
has played right guard. Now he hasn't
played right guard since his rookie
season where he was pretty much only a
right guard. Since then, his last three
years has been left guard. He has been
an inconsistent player, but he's been
consistently available, right? And
availability sometimes is your best
ability. Zion Johnson, much like Adafay
perhaps down the stretch for the
Chargers, was a guy that came on and had
a really good second half of the season
and probably made himself a lot of
money. If you believe what is reported
on the contract, what the Browns are
basically giving him in year in it's a
two-year deal. You know, call it a
three-year deal. You know, on paper,
these things are two-year deals.
Basically, year one is what the fifthear
option would have been if the Chargers
had picked it up. And year two is a
similar number. I know a lot of fans may
say, "Wait a minute, you're signing a
guy, you're signing a guy whose team
didn't pick up his fifth year option."
This happens all the time. The Ravens
didn't pick up Tyler Linderbomb's fifth
year option. Am I comparing the two? Not
necessarily. one signed for the largest
center contract in free agent in NFL
history. It's it's different math, but
Rocoan Smith didn't have his fifth year
option picked up. Okay, this happens all
the time because teams look at the
economics of the situation and go, you
know what, we'll let the guy test the
market. He did test the market and the
Browns are going to sign him. They are
better today for my money than they were
a month ago. Certainly on the offensive
line. What about Luke Whipler? My dad
says
you need depth. You don't you don't go
to battle with five offensive linemen.
Luke Whipler could very much still be in
the conversation to start depending on
whether or not Joel comes back. Jenkins
could play right guard. Zion plays left
guard if Joel retires and then Whipler
goes in as your center. And if he
doesn't, you need depth here. You're
you're not dressing five.
>> That's right. I think the other thing to
note here with all of these signings and
and the trade obviously for Titus
getting younger. I mean, you got guys
that have been in the league three,
four, five years. There's some good
durability, especially with Zion
Johnson. Um I I know that uh Elton has
been a little banged up a little bit.
I'm pulling up numbers here as I go.
>> Yeah, he broke his leg late. He had an
injury late last year,
>> but otherwise he's been pretty healthy.
But you're talking about guys between
the ages of 25 and 30 years old, which
in the NFL makes you a lot younger than
what you were on the offensive line, and
I think that's as big as anything. And
you have guys that have some good
durability that are coming in with some,
you know, good track records of staying
upright and functional.
>> Yeah. uh Titus Howard and Elton Jenkins
in the same draft, the 2019 draft. One
was a first round pick and the other was
a second round pick. They were taken
basically 20 picks apart and they're now
both sliding into the Browns offensive
line. All right, let's talk about the
Deon Bush thing because I think a lot of
Browns fans and I'll count myself in um
that that count me in there as a Browns
fan certainly and as someone who is is
in the building. I I wanted Deon Bush
back. I'm disappointed that Devin Bush
is not coming back. I wish him well. He
had a good couple of years there. He was
um like a downhill seabball killball guy
last year and he really came into his
own. He had the multiple pick sixes
including the one in week 18 in that win
in Cincinnati in which Miles got the
single season sack record. He had the
pick six against the Ravens. He had a
lot of really great moments. I wish him
well. The Bears are getting a good one.
Both can be true. I'm also kind of
excited about the Quincy Williams
signing. Last year was not his best
year. when we went to New York and I I I
don't want to bring up the memories
because that Jets game was awful on so
many levels. So many levels. We were
walking into a well Quincy Williams has
been benched situation there. It didn't
work with Aaron Glenn. Half that staff
has been fired. The Jets are now signing
every veteran piece they can find for
$10 million a year. I don't get what
they are doing, but that's another show
for another time. Quincsey Williams and
Mike Gutenberg, the Browns new defensive
coordinator, have their history from New
York. He knows this system. He has been
a very good player. He is more than just
Quinn and Williams brother.
He's a solid player who had a bad year
who I think can slide in to Devin Bush's
shoes and do the job and do it well.
>> I will miss Devin Bush.
>> Yes.
>> Uh shout out to Devin. He resurrected
his career here.
>> I mean, he saved his career.
>> Yeah.
>> It was on life support when he got here.
>> Uh and and that's a credit to him. It's
also a credit to coach Jason Tarver and
Jim Schwarz and the defensive scheme.
So, it'll be interesting to see what
happens as he goes to Chicago. If that's
the same type of defense that Chicago
runs,
>> we'll find out. But it's it is not.
We'll just say right now. It is not. the
the Dennis Allen does not run the same
front at the same system at all. Does
that mean Devin's not going to be a
success there? No.
>> No.
>> No, not at all. It'll be an adjustment
for him.
>> Yeah. I I I would say, you know, I just
I I hope it all works out for him. He's
resurrected his career. He's got some
generational wealth now. He's he's set
up and I know I know he's got a little
girl that uh is going to benefit greatly
from all of that. So, I I wish him
nothing but the best.
it. If you're not going to be able to
keep him, why not go talk to the
defensive coordinator of your football
team? Find out who he likes, what makes
the most sense. And for him, it was
Quincy Williams. And that was one of
those situations where he was an allpro.
This is a guy that that has a track
record. I mean, he's he's done some big
things. He had a bad year last year. I
think you throw that bad year out and
let let's see what happens this coming
year because he's put together some fine
seasons, 100 plus tackles in multiple
seasons. He's made plays. He's he fits
what Mike Rutenberg wants to do. And I
think Mike Rutenberg and Andrew Barry
were both on that day pretty pretty
happy. Uh I was told that uh things were
things were a little joyous in the
general manager's office when that all
went down.
>> Three years ago when he was Quincy
Williams and all pro, he had 139
tackles, 15 TFLs,
which is good. It was also three years
ago. I mean, we're not fooling
ourselves. It's okay. It's okay.
>> Maybe you need a different You're going
back to a familiar system that you have
excelled at.
Yeah, the the Browns have had success
over the years plugging in linebackers,
veteran linebackers, whether it's
Anthony Walker or Jordan Hicks or Devin
Bush. Um, obviously not all in the same
system. Um, different DCs obviously for
the first one, especially Awok. But, um,
look, you hope, cross your fingers, you
make it work here. And you hope it works
on the offensive line as well. Let's get
to our guest Gibbe, one of the new faces
on the Browns offensive line. It's
pretty cool to have this guy as our next
guest on BPA, the best podcast
available. He is the newest member.
Well, technically kind of not. Sort of,
but not everything is official as we
record this. Newest member of the Browns
offensive line. Titus Howard, welcome to
Cleveland, man.
>> Yes, sir. Nice to meet you. I know as we
sit down and do this today, you're doing
the car wash, you're shaking hands,
you're kissing babies, you got the
family there. How is that going? I'm
sure it's a lot.
>> Oh, yeah. The the process has been
pretty smooth, though. Um, you know,
just I got up early this morning. That
was the only thing. Getting up at 5:00
to do the physicals, but everybody in
the building been showing love. The
facility real nice, so I'm excited to
come back. you had said when the trade
went down that you weren't necessarily
surprised,
but it's still one thing to go, "Okay,
I'm I'm kind of ready for this." It's
another thing to like move your family.
You got a wife and four kids. Like
you're you're moving your entire life to
Cleveland. Like, can you wrap your head
around that yet?
>> Uh yeah, man. Uh it was kind of like I
kind of knew it was coming, but uh you
know when I found out uh that was
actually happening, it was going to be
the Browns and I kind of saw that coach
Warhop was a coach and I was excited uh
cuz coach coach Warhop was my coach in
2022 and every year I always told guys
he was like who's your favorite
offensive line coach? I was like coach
Warhop you know. So, I was excited, you
know, to be back here and be able to,
you know, play uh for him and, you know,
looking at, you know, the the place the
Browns in and and I see the potential
and where we're going to go and I I
heard the plan. I'm excited to be a part
of a team that can, you know, to be a
part of a team that can change things
around. So, I'm excited for the
opportunity, you know, to be here and be
a leader and lead this group. our our
guy Joe Thomas, the Hall of Famer, also
said that George Warhop was one of his
favorite O line coaches because Joe got
coached by George when when he was here
the first time. Why is he your guy?
>> Because I feel like he get the most out
of his players, you know. Um he he's all
about productivity and so he going to
coach everybody on the offensive line
the same way. Whether you're the top
paid guy, you're the practice squad, he
gonna demand your best every single day.
And I think he just holds everybody, you
know, to that same standard. Uh, and you
got to match his intensity every day.
So, if you don't, you're not able to do
that, is not the place to be. Uh, he's
not the coach for you. Uh, because, you
know, he going to demand the best for
you every day. He not going to let you
slouch off. Like, I used to always tell
guys, you know, I was a young guy when
he started coaching me. But, you know,
me and Tonsil, he coached us the same
way every day. So, you know, that made
me better as a player. Uh, made everyone
in the room respect him a lot more. And
you know, I was I was sad when he didn't
come back to Houston, but you know, we
always stayed in contact and we always
said that one day we'll get a chance,
you know, be back. So, you know, this it
>> and look at you and Tonsil now. You're
getting a new deal. Laramie is getting a
nice new deal as well in Washington.
That guy that guy not not in any way to
take away from your contract, don't get
me wrong,
>> but you guys, let's let's go
collectively. You guys have done well.
Lar's new deal, man. I'm like, "That guy
keeps winning."
>> Yeah, he he he got that contract thing
down to a T.
>> He does.
>> Every time.
>> Yes, he does.
>> Every time. He going to get that deal
done. It's going to be good. Everybody
like, "Oh, highest paid ever." Every
time.
>> Every single time. All that said, Titus,
you were the longest tenur position
player. There's a caveat. Position
player with the Texans. Hurt a little
bit to say goodbye.
>> Oh, yeah. for sure. Uh the day after the
trade, you know, um I was just, you
know, sitting at home and basically Nick
and Demo called me and we talked. They
was like, "Hey, come up to the
building." Uh you know, a lot a lot of
times guys don't get a chance to go back
in the building, you know, see everyone
before you leave. So I went up there,
got a chance to they had everybody
waiting on me, see meet, talk to
everyone for a couple hours, sat down
with Nick and De Mo. Like it's all love
there. Like you know, it was something
you know, you got to look at the
business side. sometimes you're not
going to be able to stay somewhere your
whole career,
>> but like we it's mutual respect. Uh, you
know, so I, you know, wish them nothing
but the best. Um, and vice versa, you
know, I was I'm grateful for my time in
Houston. Like everyone there was like
always good to me. So I I have no
complaint. Uh, so but I'm just excited
to be, you know, Cleveland Brown. Like
ever since I signed, I've a lot of
people hit me up, fans, media, just
people around the city, business-wise,
and it's been nothing but love and you
know, so I'm excited to be a part of
this franchise.
>> All right, let let's turn the page now.
Let's get to what matters. Titus, where
are you going to be playing, man?
>> I'm'll be a tackle.
>> Okay. Right tackle.
>> Right tackle.
>> You moved inside a little bit last year.
You played left guard and right guard.
Your versatility, I would have to think,
had to be something the Browns liked as
well. Did you feel comfortable playing
guard last year?
>> Uh, yeah, I could play guard. Um, it's
not something that I I like go to at
first, but you know, if the team needs
me, it's like something happens and the
team always had needed me to do
something, I was like, "Hey," they came
to me and like, "Hey, Tyler, we we need
you to do this." You know, I wouldn't I
was all about winning. So, you know,
whatever I had to do to win, that's what
matters the most to me. Uh, sometimes,
you know, I didn't want to go to guard,
but I did it anyways because it was the
best availability to get the win on the
game, get the best guys in the game. So,
you know, but I'm I'm at my best and I'm
most comfortable when I'm at right
tackle. And, you know, something that me
and Andrew talked about and it's
something he told me the first time we,
you know, had a conversation like, I see
you as a tackle. So,
>> you know, I'm excited to get here and
work
>> and prove out why I only want one of
this and why they paid me.
>> All right. Well, you're a team player,
too. So, I mean, that was obviously
evident last year. Any any uh coach will
tell you, let's just get our best five
on the field. That's what they were
doing last year with the Texans, and you
kicked inside. Just for the record, do
you have any more snaps at quarterback
left in you?
>> If they need me, I got you. Tell you,
hey, I got an arm, so arm ain't going to
leave.
>> Dude, you do have an arm. So, I went
down this YouTube rabbit hole last
night, Titus. So, let let me explain.
You're from Monroeville, Louisiana, like
halfway between Mobile and and
Montgomery, and you were a 6'5.
How much were you weighing back then?
Like 200.
>> If I'm going be honest with you, I
wasn't even 6'5. I was I was like 6'3. I
was like 63 around like 180, 185.
>> Okay. So, I highly encourage people,
we're going to we're going to show some
on the screen here, um to to check out
your highlights cuz dude, you're killing
people. You're this dual threat
quarterback. How many people in your
high school? It's not a big town.
>> It's not. No, it's probably like 300 or
something. 400.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> And yeah, you occasionally you you threw
some dots on those highlights, but
you're killing people. They snap it to
you and you're a bulldozer.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, we Yeah. I just tell
coach cuz first when I first got to high
school I was at tight end but then they
found out I can throw the ball and they
was like well we going to put you at
quarterback and so like from my
sophomore year all the way up to my
senior year I was just have I was
probably averaging like 150 200 rushing
yards a game like 100 120 150 passing I
I was my last career game in high school
I had like 315 yards rushing off like 15
carries with like another 200 passing.
>> Okay. So you you you remember those
numbers like it was yesterday because
that's I wrote that down. 315 yards,
correct? Uh-huh.
>> Yeah. Did you guys win?
>> It's crazy. We I had all those stats and
we still lost. I think the team put up
like 60. We put up 50. So it was crazy.
>> Did you ever, whether it was like to
Bill O'Brien or Nick Kayley or whomever,
go in there and go, "Hey, come on.
Tackle eligible. put me in motion, hand
me the ball, let me throw.
>> So, the crazy thing about that was we
always talked about me doing that, but I
always would lose the dibs to LT because
he had he was older than me. So, he was
like, hey, throw me the ball. And then
it was like, well, LT got the deals.
He's a vet. He So, they did throw the
ball against the Dolphins and he dropped
him. So, I was like, you know, I would
have I would have caught that.
>> No, no, no. I I don't want you to catch
the ball. That would be nice. Don't get
me wrong. I want you to throw the ball.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. So, a funny story about
last year, uh, we had a game against the
Bucks last year and, uh, you know, we
was they they scored like 30 seconds to
go and, you know, we get down to like
the our 30 or their 30 yard line. So, we
had like 70 yards to go and I'm we about
to get ready to go out on drive. I
walked up to the quarterback coach. I
was like, "Hey, hey, Gerard, if CJ can't
make this throw, let me know. I got
you." And they just all thought it was
so funny though. It was It was crazy.
>> Yeah, man. You You got an arm. Uh,
Monroeville, Louisiana. So, as I said,
between Mobile and Montgomery.
Birthplace of Harper Lee to Killaa
Mockingberg. Also, not far from Burnt
Corn, Alabama. You ever been to Burnt
Corn, Alabama?
>> Burnt Corn like 15 minutes away.
>> That's a real place.
>> Yeah, that's a real place.
>> Okay. Cuz I saw it on the map last
night. I'm like, that can't be real.
>> So, you got like Monroville, which is
the city. Uh, you got Franklin, Alabama,
which is where I actually stayed at
because I stayed outside the city
limits. And then you got like burnt corn
and pine view like all type of stuff
like that.
>> Okay. So there's no snow there. Not
much. Although Mobile occasionally gets
snow. Houston, you had no snow. You're
getting ready for Cleveland where
yesterday was beautiful. Like golf
weather today. Eh, we might get snow
next week or over the weekend. Are you
ready for snow? Have your kids seen
snow?
>> So my kids have seen snow twice. It
snowed in Houston twice in the last
couple years. So they got a chance to
see snow and we take a snow trip every
year like so we go to like Park City,
Utah, Breaking Ridge, Jackson Hole,
stuff like that. So you know, but as far
as like I'm ready for the cold. I mean
at the end of the day it's cool. Like
it's going to be cold. But you know it
don't last long. So
>> it does not last long.
>> When you get out on the field you don't
even think about the cold though. Only
time you think about being cold is when
you're on the sideline and then you got
you be having a warm up. But when you
get on the field, you going to be
thinking about that guy that's a cross
ring. So I'm more worried about him than
the cold.
>> The cold brings out character as my old
man used to say. Um we although we had
some road games last year where I was
questioning my character. We had a game
in Chicago where it was like one degree.
That was the temperature. Yeah. One
degree was like -15 with a win. But we
we don't need to get into that. We'll uh
we'll look forward um and look forward
to having you on the field. Titus
Howard, excited to have you. Can't wait
to see you in the offseason program and
on the field for OTAAS and mini camp and
all that fun stuff. Welcome to Cleveland
again. Best of luck, man.
>> Yes, sir. Thank you for having me.
>> Good times with Titus Howard there. So,
when all of you get anxious about the
quarterback situation, just know give a
Titus Howard could be an option. A kid
maybe not.
>> Well, but how many times last year or in
the last couple of years have we said,
"Okay, so the third quarterback isn't
up. Who's the emergency third?"
It was the It was so a couple of years
ago it was Harrison Bryant.
>> That's right.
>> Who was it last year? I had this I think
it was Blake Whiteart.
>> I think so. I
>> think it was Blake
Whiteart.
Um
>> maybe Titus can do a little bit for us.
But it also it also takes you back to to
Tom Moore, the the legendary NFL
assistant, quarterback coach, offensive
coordinators with the Colts forever. Was
was with the Bucks when when Tom Brady
circled back there at the end as well.
And Tom Moore, and I'm paraphrasing her,
basically was like, "If we have to go to
this guy, like we're bleeped." So like,
>> yeah,
>> stop asking me how many.
>> Stop asking stop asking how we're going
to navigate. We're not going to navigate
it. Why the third stringer is not
getting enough reps in practice of the
second stringer. It doesn't matter if
Pton Manning goes down.
>> It doesn't matter. Exactly. That's a
better way to say it. You're a broadcast
professional. It doesn't matter. I'm not
a Hall of Famer
>> at at that point. Neither am I. I'm just
a guy that they gave an award to. It's
over there. It's a plaque. It's lovely.
Um
>> yeah, I think Titus Howard's going to be
a great fit. I do think even though he
he seems he seems set on right tackle
and that's likely where he goes. um his
position flexibility because injuries do
happen both in-game and and midweek um
is is a huge plus. Let's go around the
AFC North. Uh we still don't know as of
this hour the Steelers quarterback
situation. Honestly, call me when they
figure it out. I'm done talking about
it. Um as for the Bengals, I I like
their Boyet Maf edition. I like their
Brian Cook edition. Cincinnati native by
the way, and he's a Bearcat as well. I
don't know the price tag on Boyet Maf.
That's a little bit bonkers for me. And
then Gibbe, there is the curious case of
Matt Crosby, Trey Hendrickson, and the
Baltimore Ravens. Let's just let you
talk first. What do you think?
Like you, I I was like, wow, that's uh
that's a hell of a move by the Ravens um
at the 11th hour to change things.
Actually, I think it was at the 1:00
hour. I think you were past midnight. Um
I the only what what I brought up today
I was playing devil's advocate in our
office. I said how can you prove that
the Ravens,
you know, didn't believe that he wasn't
going to be a factor or that the injury
was severe enough. You can't you can't
prove that their medical staff didn't
say, "Okay, like we're not sure if he
can recover completely from this injury.
We need to maybe back out of this."
Every medical staff's different. There's
32 medical staff. No universal
>> system or no way of doing this.
>> Do I think it's looks shady? Absolutely.
>> But I you can't how do you prove it?
>> Both can be true. It's not a good way to
do business. And they might have been
terrified after looking at that knee.
And it's it's not a question of whether
or not he could pass the physical right
now. Everyone knows. Everybody knows
here Max Crosby can't play football
today and the Ravens knew that as well.
It's about looking at everything and
saying, "Oh, we we think he's going to
get back to the same form." It it also
could be, and this is, you know, pure
speculation. Hey guys, he'll be okay,
but we think he's got like one year left
on on these tires. I'm going to use a
bad car analogy, right? Like this
engine's about to fall through the
floor. So, it might be a year. It might
be a great year, but that's it. Again,
pure speculation. the Ravens are within
their rights and it's a bad way to do
business. Both can absolutely be and are
true. Also, the Raiders wrote all these
contracts or at least agreed to terms on
all these contracts and now they get Max
Crosby back and that was math that they
had not planned for. Now, I threw that
out on the socials when all this broke
on Tuesday and a lot of Raider fans who
who use colorful language, who knew,
came back at me that I don't understand
the cap. Like, no people, that's not the
case. That there's nothing to do with
that. Actually, I didn't answer because
just step away.
>> It's not about whether or not they have
the cap. The Raiders can make the cap
work bringing Max Crosby back. It It's
more so the cash. Cash and cap are
different things, and they had not
planned for writing a $30 million check
this year to Max Crosby. That's
different from the cap. Also, people
say, "Oh, the Ravens had this up their
sleeve, and now they get out of it, and
now they get Trey Hendricks, and they're
the huge winner." They let nine of their
own free agents walk. We're just sitting
here lamenting losing Devin Bush. They
let nine of their guys walk.
>> Did they want all nine back? Probably
not. Did they want Tyler Lindab back?
Absolutely.
They let nine guys go. So, the idea that
they're all of a sudden smelling like
roses and Oh, what a sneaky move. Like,
nobody looks good through all of this.
Nobody. No. So, I was looking I'm
looking through my phone right now. Uh,
Rap Sheet had a had a tweet that
basically was it the 2022 draft class
for the Ravens?
Six guys.
>> All those guys got paid.
>> Yeah, that basically it was like $260
million.
>> Yeah, all those guys got paid. Tyler
Lindab, though, and and if I'm the
Ravens, I'm mildly upset at the Raiders
or the rest of the league for absolutely
blowing the center market out of the
water. The highest paid center was 18
million. Creed Humphrey 18.
>> And I think Linder fifth like seven like
there's a steep drop off from there.
>> Yeah. 50% raise. It went from 18 to 27.
I don't begrudge him. That's great
American work. If you can get it, God
bless. Like I I do I do a Yahoo show. My
friend Jory Epstein led the show on
Monday with it is a good day to be a
center. Absolutely. So like like there
are so many crazy moving parts in all
this in free agency. And it's not the
first time that a deal fell apart. Frank
Gore changed his mind.
>> Yeah.
>> Josh McDaniels far different changed his
mind. Players can change their mind.
deals aren't. Last year, Milton Williams
is going to the Carolina Panthers until
the Patriots stepped in. Now, this is
only a couple hours later, all on
Monday, the Patriots stepped in, up the
Annie. Okay,
now he's going to the Patriots. It
turned out okay for them. I tweeted at
the start of free agency. Happy new
Happy Free agency friends. Friendly
reminder, nothing is official until 4
p.m. Eastern time,
>> which is why the NFL needs to change
this garbage. What's going to change?
>> Picked it off Monday at noon. Like
trades can trades can start at noon. You
can't start talking.
>> You realize that's what the old system
was and everyone tampered.
>> And so announced it's legal tampering.
Your favorite term.
>> So at 12:01 under the old system, all
these deals got done at the combine in
the dark corners of steakouses at 2 in
the morning. And then at 12:01 they were
announced and people went, "Wait a
minute. I I thought free agency just
opened.
Wait, wait, wait. How did this deal get
done? In 25 seconds. How did this get
done? Because there was tampering. So,
what the league just said is we'll let
everyone negotiate starting at X hour,
but nothing becomes official.
I don't mind the current system. I
really don't. I really don't.
>> I I think it's I I think it's broken.
Just
>> find me a better system
>> today. today at uh today we're taping on
a Wednesday.
>> Yeah.
>> At 4:00
>> it's all done
>> or the bulk of it is done.
>> So whatever you call the system, the
system begins at 12:00
or on Monday.
>> Just they allow teams to to say deals
can't. I don't know, man.
>> Dude, there's there's no good way to do
it. I don't like
>> we can go to an NBA system where you're
allowed to trade 35 first round draft
picks and put all these like
modifications on the deal. Well, if we
tank too much, you can't have the pick.
But if we only do a medium tank, then
you can have the pick. I mean, it's
>> Well, and here's the thing. Even if you
make a trade, it takes multiple days to
find the player if they're on vacation,
get them in the building and and get
them, you know, get the physical and all
that. I mean, that's why the Max Crosby
stuff didn't break till last night. You
know, it broke on a Tuesday night. The
trade happened on a Friday night, but
you got to get him in the building. You
have to get him from wherever he's at,
fly him in, make all the arrangements.
I like it. It just I You're right. I
don't know. I don't know what the fix
is, but I do know that it's going to
cost the Raiders a lot of money. And if
you're Baltimore, maybe some of that
money could have been used to keep some
of your guys
>> guys. Yeah. Now there there is a
positive spin here for the Raiders
potentially. Like they went out and they
signed all these guys,
>> right? They're a better team now. And
they did spend more on younger guys.
Quay Walker and Nico Dean, not like
necessarily what the Jets did, signing
all these old pieces. And then you could
add Max Crosby back to it. If you can
make the money work, okay, like in the
end, maybe it's a bit of a blessing.
Weird way to get there. But maybe
there's a world in which it works. But
if I'm one of the teams that were trying
to get Max Crosby and didn't get him and
the Ravens got him and I'm calling back
up, I'm going, I'm not paying you the
same thing they did,
right? I'm paying you 60 cents on the
dollar.
>> That's another edition of the best
podcast available. It's brought to you
by Bullseye Event Group. For
award-winning game day experiences,
visit bullseyeventgroup.com.
Give a fun. Let's do one next week.
Maybe the Browns will make more moves. I
have no doubt there will be new news.
New news.
>> No, Travis Kelce is not going to be a
Brown.
>> No, you thought may It was never going
to happen.
>> Not Not going to happen. It would have
been nice
>> like a a goodbye reunion tour wearing
Andre Davis his old number the wide
receiver Andre Davis not the linebacker
Andre Davis
>> with with an A
>> or was that the defense that was the
offensive player right?
>> Yeah. Off
>> Virginia Tech was the wide receiver.
Chris Rose and I, fun fact were at that
game at Candlestick when he caught the
Kelly Hulkcom pass with a minute
remaining in the back of the end zone to
beat the 49ers.
That's a That's a moment. He had a
couple moments. Was a solid wide
receiver.
>> Yeah. Whatever year that was, like
02ish,
>> whatever.
>> Now we're dating ourselves.
>> Well,
I mean, there's so many jokes there
about dating oneself.
>> That's right.
>> Enough. Enough about my personal life.
Uh, this has been BPA.
That's Jason Gibbs. I'm Andrew
Siciliano.
Talk to you next time, friends.